### **JOSHUA MORGAN**

FULL STACK DEVELOPER - React.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB Linkedin | GitHub

Greenville, SC 29650 864-404-1515 joshuamorgan0605@gmail.com

### Summary

I am a **full stack developer** specializing in **React**, **Node.js** (**Express.js**), **MongoDB**, and **Jest**. My current interests include **Next.js**, **TypeScript**, **Cypress.io**, **React Testing Library**, and **Storybook**. I have **3 years** of experience in the JavaScript ecosystem. And I have built and worked on web applications geared toward the general public and general industry.

## **Projects**

### In-Season Produce Project ( Code I View Site )

#### May 2023 - November 2023

A full stack **Node.js** (**Express**), **React** application for the person seeking to find in-season local produce.

- Developed **RESTful API** to control user functions using **Express.js** with **MongoDB** as a persistence layer while utilizing **React** on the frontend.
- Incorporated **React Router v6** for client-side routing, providing faster user experiences.
- Managed remote data w/ **React Query** simplifying data fetching, caching, and synchronization.
- Enforced secure data transfer protocols and encryption mechanisms and ensured user data remained protected via **JWT Tokens** and **HTTP Cookies**.

## React Job Simulator ( <u>Code</u> I <u>View Site</u> )

#### December 2023 - March 2024

Took part in job simulation program designed by Sr. React developed. Worked on error logging and monitoring tool built with **Next.js** framework, **React**, and **TypeScript**.

- Completed feature requests from Kanban board simulating professional work environment.
- Wrote automated tests with Cypress, improving proper project design and function.
- Wrote automated tests with Cypress, improving proper project design and function.
- Built UI kit based on Figma designs, creating pixel-perfect rendering.

## **Experience**

#### **Berkshire Hathaway**

2017 - 2020

### Licensed Real Estate Agent – Summerville, SC

• Supported buyers and sellers in process of purchasing or selling residential property.

### **Spartanburg Day School**

2013 - 2016

#### **Upper School VISTAS Teacher** – Spartanburg, SC

Supported learning disabled students (ADHD, Aspergers, Dyslexia, etc) in acquiring and applying
the skills and know-how to succeed in a college-preparatory classroom, improving letter grades
and confidence.

### Hanalani Schools 2010 – 2011

#### **Upper School Instructor** — Mililani Town, HI

• Built 10th grade English curriculum that conveyed core content while also inspiring collaboration, adaptive problem-solving skills, critical thinking, communication, and positive digital citizenship.

# **Evangelical Christian School**

2007 - 2009

**Upper School Instructor** — Fort Myers, FL

- Tailored Theology curriculum, giving students a personal and appropriate learning experience.
- Develop curriculum for Keyboarding class, leaving students with a comprehensive and interactive course.

### **Education**

Full Stack Software Engineering Launch School (Link)	June 2020 - Feb 2023
<b>Elementary Teacher Certification</b> USC Upstate — Spartanburg, SC	Aug 2011 — May 2012
<b>Masters of Arts in Teaching</b> Bob Jones University – Greenville, SC	Aug 2004 – May 2007